Guide to the Cletus Daniel Papers 1937-1991
Daniel, Cletus, Papers
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Cletus Daniel Papers, 1937-1991
/4288
Daniel, Cletus
5 linear ft.
Papers.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
This is a collection of research material that Professor Daniel collected during his tenure at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Daniel, Cletus E., 1943-
Subjects:
Collective bargaining; Labor laws and legislation; Labor--History
Form and Genre Terms:
Papers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
/4073: James O. Morris Office Files
/4290m: ILR School Dean's Office Memorial Statements
/4297: ILR School Biography Files
5584: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers
5584 A: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers
5619/008: ACWA Rieve-Pollock Foundation Files
5981 P: ACTWU Labor Unity Photograph Files
CONTAINER LIST
- The A.C.L.U. and the Wagner Act: An Inquiry Into the Depression-Era Crisis of American Liberalism (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Chapter X Factories in the Field- Donald Von Eschon, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Chapter I-IV (Folder 1 of 2), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Chapter I-IV (Folder 2 of 2), 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Politics of Inequality: The President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice and Chicago Workers during World War II, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Politics of Inequality: The President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice and Chicago Workers during World War II, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notes (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Daniel Course Evaluations (Box 1, Folder 8)
- In Defense of the Wheatland Wobblies: A Critical Analysis of the I.W.W. in California (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ILR 689, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  `
- ACLU Proposal Amendments to A.A.A. and NLRA, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Wagner Bill, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Sacramento C.S. Cases, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- ACLU & Wagner Act Debate, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Farm Workers Collective Bargaining Rights A 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Notes, Documents Relating to Labor, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Papers Relating to Labor + Unions in the 1930s, 1936-1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- San Jose Cannery Strike, 1931 RGB 170-6504 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- El Monte Strike, 1933 RG 13 170-8083 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- In Defense of the Wheatland Wobblies: A Critical Analysis of the I.W.W. in California & Articles from The New Republic, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Harper's, Amer. Marquis, Amer. Mag, 1934-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- The New Republic+ American Federationist, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- ACLU Vol. 6/13, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- IJA Monthly Bulletins Reel 5 1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- ACLU Vol. 772, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- ACLU Vol. 719, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ACLU Vol. 718, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- ACLU Vol. 705, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- ACLU Vol. 775, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- ACLU Vol. 706, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- ACLU Vol. 598, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- ALCU Vol. 607, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- ACLU Record Reels 3 and 4, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- ACLU Vol. 721, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- ACLU Record Reel 4 Minutes 1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- ACLU Vol 698, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- ACLU Record Reel 4 Press Releases 1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- ACLU Records Reel 5 Press Bulletins 1933 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- ACLU Vol. 618, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- ACLU Vol. 696, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- ACLU Vol 777, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- IJA Bulletins 1937 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- ACLU Records Reel 5 Press Bulletins 1934 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Communist 1934 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Communist 1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- IJA Monthly Bulletins 1934 Reel 5 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- ACLU Records Reel 5 Minutes 1934 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- ACLU Vol. 780, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- ACLU Records Reel 31 Policy Guides 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- ACLU Vol. 784, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Transactions of the California State Agriculture Society + Other Docs., 1880-1904 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Transactions of the California State Agricultural Society, 1880-1905 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Transactions of the California State Agricultural Society+ Other Docs. Relating to Labor in the USA, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- UCA pawa - 1937 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Milwaukee Co. Ind. Union Council, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- RG 13 /99-1189 Pecan Shellers Strike, 1938 U.S. Amer. Service, 1933-1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Saturday Review + Prof. Daniel's Document, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- FERA in California 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Filipino Veg. Workers' Strike, 1931 U.S. Cm. Service RG 13 170-6125 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Imperial Valley Situation, 1932 RG 13 170-725 US Cm. Service (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Proceedings of Meeting No.1 of the Special Industrial Recovery Road + Some Other Letters to Gov. Officials, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Seabrook Strike, 1934 RG 13 170-9817 U.S. Com. Service (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Legal Cases Relating to Agricultural Workers in California, 1939-1945 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Papers+ Newspapers Relating to Labor, Workers, + Unions in the USA, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Most newspaper clippings very delicate
- Material Relating to the I.W.W.+ Labor Articles Relating to Agriculture, 1913-1917 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Howell "The IWW and the Espionage Act" (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Notes and Papers Relating to Labor+ Agriculture in California, 1915-1921 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- List of References on Migrants and Related Subjects in the SRA Library, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Social Science Research Council Bibliography of P.C. Agri Labor (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Papers Relating to Agriculture and Labor, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Agricultural Workers and the AAA, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Farm Workers Support, 1931-38, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Philip Bancroft Interviews (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Wofford B, Camp Interviews, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Papers Relating to the Wagner Act + Labor Journals, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Imperial Valley Strikes, 1930 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 170-5463, 1939-1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Preface+ Chapter 1-4 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Origins of Powerlessness: California Farmworkers in the Age of Organization and Reform- Chapter 4-8 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Newspapers, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Speeches, etc. Supporting Agricultural Unionism, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Reports, etc. on Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Oxnand Beet Workers' Strike, 1933 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 170-9201 176-413 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Communist Party Materials, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Fresno Bee+ s-f Examine + Letter, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- ACLU and 1933 Cotton Strikes (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Anti-Filipino Activities in Salinas Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- ACLU Correspondence with Gen. Glassford WPA/FNP, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Internal ACLU Correspondence Re Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Materials re Imperial Valley, 1933 Strikes, Growers Activities, etc., 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondences in Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Imperial Valley, 1934 RG 13 170-7205 U.S. Com. Service (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Orange Pickers' Strike, 1936 U.S. Com Service RG 13 182-1525 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Creed Correspondence, other materials re 1933 Cotton Strike and Aftermath, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Cotton Strike, 1933 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 176-635, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Mexican Labor Union, 1934 RG 13 170-7205 U.S. Com. Service (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Agricultural Labor Relations in General, mid 1934 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Salinas Strikes, 1928-1935 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 176-654 182-931 170-4693 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Cotton Pickers, San Joaquin Valley, 1935-37 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 182-763 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- American Federation of Labor, Report of Proceedings, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Materials re NLB Activism in Salinas Valley, 1934, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Agricultural Labor Disputes, Salhen California, 1935 U.S. Com. Service RG 13 182-77, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- ACLU Efforts to get Federal Achieve in Imperial Valley, 1934, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Materials From Justice Dept. Re Federal Interpretation in Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Articles Relating to Agriculture and Labor, 1937-1939 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Speeches, etc. Against Agricultural Unionism, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- San Maria Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Anti-Farm Labor Activities of State Government., June, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- C.A.W.I.U. Materials, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Fed. Govt. and Calif. Red Scare, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Sacramento C.S. Cases, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Internal ACLU Correspondence on Imperial Valley, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Materials re States of Farm Labor Under NIRA Sec.7 (a), 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Los Angles Regional Labor Board Materials in Imperial Valley, 1934 RG 25, NLB,IX,NA (Box 4, Folder 35)
- US Department of Labor Reports + Articles Relating to Labor, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Salinas Lettuce Packers' Strike- 1936 U.S. Conciliation Service File No. 182-1416 Record Group 13, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- In Defense of the Wheatland Wobblies (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Yakima Valley Strikes- 1933 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Newbill Article on Yakima Strike, 1910-1936 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Articles Relating to Labor, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Writings by Prof. Cletus Daniel + Agricultural Economic Bibliographies (Folder 1 of 4), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Agricultural Economic Bibliographies (Folder 2 of 3), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Agricultural Economic Bibliographies (Folder 3 of 3), 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Yakima and the Wobblies, 1910-1936 By James G. Newbill (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Professor Evaluations for Prof. Cletus Daniel, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Cornell Inventory for Student Appraisal of Teaching and Courses, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Professor Evaluations for Prof. Cletus Daniel (Box 5, Folder 7)
- The Politics of Inequality: The President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice and Chicano Workers During World War II, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Pacific Northwest Quarterly, and Minutes of the Regular Meetings on the Los Angeles Industrial Union Council, CIO, 1937-1940 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Minutes of the Regular Meeting of the Los Angeles, Industrial Union Council, CIO, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Reference Lists (Folder 1 of 4), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Reference Lists (Folder 2 of 4), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Reference Lists- Agriculture (Folder 3 of 4), 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Reference Lists- Agriculture (Folder 4 of 4), 1953 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- An Injury to One is an Injury to Some: Inter-Union Relations in the U.S. Airline Industry, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 15)